Raymond Selent

Data Scientist

Passionate, fast-learning Data Professional with strong Python, analytical, and hat-wearing skills, adding communication & customer service skills from 10+ years in IT consultancy and a creative approach to problem solving honed from studies in film, broadcasting, and theatre.

rselent@ufl.edu	\searrow
954.990.3121	
Fort Lauderdale, FL	Q
rselent.github.io	

linkedin.com/in/rselent in

github.com/rselent ()

EDUCATION

Data Science, Machine Learning, & Computer Science

Lambda School

11/2019 - 08/2020 Remote

CodeSignal GCA Score: 651

Theatre

University of Florida

08/2014 - 05/2018 Gainesville, FL

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Dramaturg

UF School of Theatre + Dance

01/2018 - 05/2018

- Organized research & analysis of Restoration comedy The Beaux' Stratagem & all related topics
- Supported and empowered a team of 24+ cast & crew members, generating head- and mind-space for greater artistry, imagination, and originality in all production-oriented workflows
- Triaged questions from cast & crew and delivered answers, research findings, insights, and notes during daily rehearsals & production meetings

Virtual Chief Information Officer (vCIO)

Self-Employed

01/2006 - 01/2018

Advised & maneuvered SBE & professional customers through rapidly changing technology landscapes with customer-focused, white glove IT services

- Partnered with business leaders to understand needs & challenges and discover root causes
- Recommended forward-looking actions, linking IT with business objectives and identifying impacts of potential trends & opportunities
- Developed custom CRM software (Python2.x) to improve tracking of customer data

SKILLS



DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

Feelings Detector – Data Scientist (02/2021 - Present)

- Building neural network model that recognizes & classifies emotions based on affective science principles, utilizing & selfteaching TensorFlow and OpenFace API
- Training model on RAVDESS dataset, consisting of 2400+ CSVs
- Implementing computer vision pipeline between OpenFace API output and classification model
- Designing visualizations that measure impacts of new product features

Project Canopy – Data Scientist Engineer (03/2020 - 05/2020)

- Led & advocated for 4-person Data team inside 14-member crossfunctional Project team: established roadmaps & strategy with Project Lead and reassessed milestones when needed
- Collaborated & partnered with Stakeholders and Frontend, Backend, and UX teams to create desired reporting platform & continually improve user experience within 8-week timeline
- Architected & built custom ETL pipeline: identified 20 APIs & data sources, extracted & cleaned data, designed database structure, and warehoused data in Amazon RDS-hosted PostgreSQL database
- Executed on product request for model predicting future endangered species, by exploiting observed gaps in crosssectional data

P-H-A Assistant – Machine Learning Engineer (01/2020)

- Built, evaluated, tested, debugged, and deployed prediction model web app to Heroku within 4 days while also self-teaching needed technologies like Flask, Plotly, and Heroku
- Through time-sensitive research, strengthened domain knowledge to appropriately understand and analyze large-scale dataset, self-sourced from NASA-JPL's Small-Body Database